There's a new way to be wicked.
Descendants: The Rise of Red is a fantasy, adventure,
family film directed by Jennifer Phang.
After the Queen of Hearts incites a coup on Auradon, her rebellious daughter Red and Cinderella's perfectionist daughter Chloe join
forces and travel back in time to try to undo the traumatic event that set Red's mother down her villainous path.
Princess Red, played by Kylie Cantrall.
Chloe, played by Malia Baker.
Bridget, played by Ruby Rose Turner.
Ella, played by Morgan Dudley.
Uliana, played by Dara Reneé.
Queen of Hearts, played by Rita Ora.
Descendants: The Rise of Red is a 2024 American musical teen fantasy comedy film
directed by Jennifer Phang from a screenplay by Dan Frey and Ru Sommer.
Produced by Disney Channel, the film is the fourth installment in the Descendants franchise, being a
spin-off of the previous three films and a follow-up from Descendants: The Royal Wedding (2021).
The film was released on Disney+ on July 12, 2024, and made
its debut on Disney Channel on August 9, 2024.
Kylie Cantrall and Malia Baker star as Red (daughter of Queen of Hearts from Alice in Wonderland) and
Chloe Charming (daughter of Cinderella and Prince Charming from Cinderella), respectively.
China Anne McClain and Melanie Paxson reprise their roles of Uma and Fairy
Godmother, respectively, from previous Descendants films.
Cinderella and King Charming are played by Brandy and Paolo Montalban, who previously played
versions of the characters in the 1997 television adaptation of Cinderella.
Descendants: The Rise of Red received generally mixed reviews from critics.
With 6.7 million views in its first three days of streaming, the film broke a record in its debut on
Disney+ as Disney Branded Television's most-viewed premiere ever on the platform.
The film later demonstrated substantial streaming viewership, leading as the top streaming original
movie for a week and maintaining strong rankings throughout July and early August 2024.
It became Disney+'s most-streamed live-action
original movie since Hocus Pocus 2.
A sequel, Descendants: Wicked Wonderland, is scheduled for release in 2026.
The film explores themes of descendant, time
travel, musical, spin off, cinderella.
The tone is lighthearted.